pascalegourdeau

computer science student

about

Montreal, Qc Canada

McGill email personal website Twitter

languages

bilingual french/english intermediate spanish

programming

Python C, Java, SML CSS3 & HTML5

interests

machine learning, discrete mathematics, theory of computation, health and social applications of computer science, research, social justice, dance

education

since 2012 Bachelor of Science McGill University, Montreal

Honours Computer Science, minor in Mathematics

CGPA: 3.95/4

2010–2012 IB Diploma Lester B. Pearson UWC of the Pacific, Victoria (BC)

Admitted on full scholarpship

Grade: 41/42 subject points, 42/45 total

2005–2010 **Diplôme d'études secondaires** Collège Notre-Dame, Montréal

(Secondary School Diploma)

experience

2014-... Research Internship, Reasoning and Learning Lab McGill University

05 2015-...: Minimization and approximation algorithms on Singular Value

Automata (automata theory and singular value decomposition).

05 2014-...: Machine Learning classification algorithms to predict extubation

readiness in exteme preterm infants.

06–08 2013 Art Supervisor and Performer. Max Bell Theatre Company, Edinburgh UK

Play: The Gypsybird Speaks

Responsible for the props and the set; dancer

distinctions

2015 Anita Borg Memorial Scholarship Google

Scholarship recognizing women's contribution and leadership in Computer

Science and Software Engineering.

value of \$5000

2015 Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council (NSERC) Under-

graduate Student Research Award

McGill University

Summer research in the Reasoning and Learning Lab

value of \$5625

2014 Science Undergraduate Research Award McGill University

Summer research in the Reasoning and Learning Lab

value of \$5600

2010–2012 Full scholarship to attend Lester B. Pearson UWC United World Colleges

International boarding school network working towards peace and a sustain-

able future value of \$80.000

2010 General Governor Medal Collège Notre-Dame, Montreal

Academic Performance prize

extracurricular

since 2014	VP Diversity – Computer Science Undergraduate Society McGill University Organize up to 5 events per semester, promote diversity and equity in the student body, attend CSUS meetings and participate and volunteer in the council's activities, act as liaison to other Equity Commissioners on campus
since 2014	Hackathons McHacks (McGill University): top 10 out of 85 teams HackPrinceton (Princeton University) More info
since 2014	Women in STEM volunteering Promoting Opportunities for Women in Engineering (POWE): volunteer during the POWE Conference for Future Women in Engineering – McGill University Volunteer for a full-day HTML/CSS workshop for girls – Girls Learning Code
since 2012	VP Promotion – United World Colleges Overlook promotion efforts, organize presentations at secondary schools, participate in the selection process to choose new scholarship recipients
2013 – 2014	Executive member, Administrative Council Website maintenance, social media, communications
06–08 2011	Volunteer in a palliative care home Cooking for the patients and their family La maison Desjardins du KRTB

research

12 2014	Women in Machine Learning Conference Montreal
	Poster presentation on Using Machine Learning to Predict Extubation Readi-
	ness in Extreme Preterm Infants
10 2014	Undergraduate Research Conference (URC) McGill University, Montreal
	Selected to represent Computer Science at the URC, a conference organized
	by the Faculty of Science (top 5 summer research projects)